Guide to the Oregon State University Military Photographs Collection 1875-1975
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- World War Two, 1940-1945; Series IV
  - Portraits of military officers and NCOs ROTC Alumni, circa 1944
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Spencer, circa 1944; P002:312; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Major Spencer (No other identification)
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Minton, circa 1925; P002:313; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Minton 103 Also listed as circa 1925, which is possible due to high collar tunic with Sam Browne belt, Cavalry officer This photo of Captain J T Minton, Cavalry, appears in the 1927 Beaver Yearbook pg. 256 under the group of Commissioned US Army officers at OAC.
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Lovett, circa 1925; P002:314; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Lovett 103 Small oval photo, probably of 1920s vintage, officer badge for Engineers. This photo of 1st Lt. R. G. Lovett, Engineers appears in the 1927 Beaver Yearbook pg. 256 under the group of Commissioned US Army officers at OAC.
    - Portrait US Army Officer McCormick, circa 1925; P002315; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: McCormick 103 Oval photo with officer cap with brim, high collar and Artillery badge. This photo of Captain T. C. Mc McCormick, Field Artillery appears in the 1927 Beaver Yearbook pg. 256 under the group of Commissioned US Army officers at OAC.
    - Portrait US Army officer - Russey, circa 1925; P002:316; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Russey 103 Oval photo, high collar with artillery badge. This photo of Captain J W Russey Field Artillery appears in the 1927 Beaver Yearbook pg. 256 under the group of Commissioned US Army officers at OAC.
    - Portrait US Army NCO - Force, circa 1944; P002:317; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Force, J. A. M/Sgt ROTC #52230
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Bryan, circa 1944; P002:318; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Bryan #51402 (no other identification, subject is a Major or Lt. Colonel, US Army Air Corps badges)
    - Portrait US Army NCO - Jones, circa 1944; P002:319; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Jones, Loren ROTC #51398
    - Portrait US Army NCO - Johnson, circa 1944; P002:320; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Johnson, E. W. M/Sgt ROTC #52227
    - Portrait USMC Officer - Skinner, circa 1944; P002:322; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Lt. W. R. Skinner (No other identification, USMC officer, probably OSC alumni)
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Brinkman, circa 1944; P002:323; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Brinkman, M. N. Capt. #49959
    - Portrait US Navy Officer - Claudnis, circa 1944; P002:324; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Claudnis, H. G. #49958 (US Navy uniform, officer?, ROTC?)
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Latson, circa 1925; P002:321; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Latson 103 (oval photo, high collar with Engineers badge, probably Pre 1925) This photo of 1st Lt. R. G. Miller, Field Artillery appears in the 1927 Beaver Yearbook pg. 256 under the group of Commissioned US Army officers at OAC.
    - Portrait US Army Officer - Miller, circa 1925; P002:326; 3X5 photographic print (Box 2)
      Stock portrait from US Army. Name of person in this photograph is listed as: Miller 103 (Oval photo, high collar with artillery badge, probably Pre 1925)
  - Negatives - World War Two photographs 1940-1945
    Collection of 4x5 negatives, various subjects during WWII years (1940-1945). Many of the negatives correspond with prints in this series. Some of the negatives are related to the prints as different views, same topics. Arranged numerically within the sub series folder. Many negatives in this sub series appear in OSC publications (Yearbook, Oregon Stater, Barometer)
    - Governor Sprague at Military Review May 1941 Color Guard with 2 Officers, circa 1941; P002:045; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Military review outside Weatherford Hall on parade field. Color guard coming to halt in front of two Officers. Prior description of image dates it to May 1941 with a review by Governor Sprague. Similar photographs are seen in the 1941 OSC Beaver Yearbook, page 95.
      Sprague, Charles Arthur, Governor, November 12, 1887 – March 13, 1969
    - Governor Sprague at Military Review May 1941, circa 1941; P002:046; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Military review of cadets marching past line of officers and officials. Prior description of photo dates it to May 1941 with a visit by Governor Sprague. Color guard with national flag and Oregon State College flag. Uniforms of officers in reviewing line are inconclusive as to dating. Buildings in the background of parade grounds are no help. Photographs can be seen in the 1941 OSC Beaver Yearbook, page 95.
    - Governor Sprague Reviewing Cadet Officers May 1941, circa 1941; P002:047; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Review of ranks of cadet officers by Governor Sprague. Reviewing line has good detail of uniforms of NCO and cadets. Weatherford Hall in background with crowd in attendance. Photographs can be seen in the 1941 OSC Beaver Yearbook, page 95, some were not used in publication.
    - Governor Sprague Reviewing Cadets May 1941, circa 1941; P002:048; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      OSC Cadets in review on parade field passing Governor Sprague and other dignitaries. Prior dating of the event to May of 1941 is possible based on uniforms. Good detail of cadet drill team marching past reviewing stand, with command "eyes left". Guidon cadet lowering unit flag for review. Patch on uniforms may lead to a positive dating. Photographs can be seen in the 1941 OSC Beaver Yearbook, page 95.
    - Army Procurement Committee on MU Steps, circa 1942; P002:050; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Large grouping of students and military personnel posed on steps of Memorial Union. Prior identification of photo dates it to October of 1942. Two conifer trees adjacent to steps of MU (approx 15-20 feet) could possibly date photo. Everyone seems to be in winter clothing.
    - Cadet officers pulling ballots for Military Ball, circa 1942; P002:052; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      2 cadet officers and NCO advisor pulling ballots for the Military Ball, probably 1942-43. Ballots for the "Little Colonel" queen of the ball. Dress uniforms indicate WWII vintage. Location of photograph is in the Memorial Union.
    - Strand, August reviewing cadets at Military Review with officers, circa 1944; P002:054; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      President August L. Strand and military officers reviewing cadet color guard on parade, circa 1944. The Colonel is wearing the late WWII "Ike" Jacket, other officers wearing WWII vintage dress uniforms. Military review of cadet formations on parade grounds adjacent to Weatherford Hall. Possible use of these negatives for the Beaver Yearbook (this photo unpublished, but others of the same event are in 1945 Beaver)
    - US Army Cadets on review field with military officers, circa 1944; P002:055; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      US Army officers reviewing cadets on parade field, circa 1944. The Colonel reviewing cadets is wearing the late WWII "Ike" jacket uniform coat. Other officers indicate late WWII dress uniform coats. Cadets are on parade field adjacent to Weatherford hall, formations are lined up for inspection by commander. Possible use for the Beaver Yearbook (this photo unpublished, but others of the same event are in 1945 Beaver)
    - Schuld, Marshall receiving award, circa 1945; P002:056; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Officer shaking hand of man (Marshall Schuld ?) with medal. Unconfirmed identification, possibly a stock photo used in Oregon Stater during period? Military uniform of colonel is WWII or later vintage.
    - Review for Captain Beard (Band) circa 1945, P002:057; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Unconfirmed description of a review for Captain Beard, circa 1945. Line of military officers are in late WWII dress uniforms including the late war "Ike" jacket. Possible use of the negatives for the Beaver Yearbook (this photo unpublished, but others of the same event are in 1945 Beaver)
    - Group of young men swearing in ceremony, circa 1942; P002:068; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Army officer swearing in a group of young men on campus
    - ROTC Commandants Scott and Webster 1945, circa 1945; P002:069; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Two US Army officers, identified as the ROTC Commandants, 1945 named Scott and Webster. Uniforms are correct for the post 1944 issue of the short "Ike" jacket.
    - Group of five Military officers, circa 1943; P002:448; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Group shot of five military officers (2 Navy, 2 Army, 1 USMC). Possibly the assigned military personnel to OSC ROTC program.
    - Group photo of ROTC officers with rifles, saluting, circa 1943; P002:449; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Group of 11 ROTC personnel with rifles saluting, taken in front of Armory. Uniforms indicate WWII vintage, men are wearing garrison caps.
    - ROTC Cadets with rifles at attention, circa 1943; P002:450; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Squad of ROTC Cadets with company commander at attention with rifles. Men are wearing the standard garrison caps and class A tunics. The rifles are M1903 Springfield, issued to cadet units.
    - ROTC Cadet band playing on parade field, circa 1943; P002:451; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      OSC ROTC Cadet band playing on parade field with conductor standing on chairs. WWII Era uniform style on conductor shows belted tunic and standard service cap.
    - Inspection day, Gov. Sprague reviews cadets, circa 1941; P002:452; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing cadet formations.
    - Soldiers running on parade field with rifles, circa 1941; P002:459; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Cadets running on parade field with rifles, demonstration of tactics.
    - Dignitaries reviewing troops on inspection day, circa 1941; P002:461; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing cadet formations. Circa dating of uniforms would indicate early WWII period.
    - Governor Sprague reviewing cadets, circa 1941; P002:462; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Dignitaries salute passing colors, circa 1941; P002:465; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Cadet formations pass in review, circa 1941; P002:472; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Governor reviewing cadet color guard, circa 1941; P002:474; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing cadet formations. Unfortunately the Governor's hat is covering his face, preventing positive identification.
    - Dignitaries reviewing ROTC officers, circa 1941; P002:475; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Governor Sprague reviews color guard, circa 1941; P002:476; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing cadet formations. Possibly President Strand is following him (Unconfirmed).
    - OSC Cadet Band playing for Inspection Day, circa 1941; P002:477; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. OSC Band playing on parade field with dignitaries in background.
    - Dignitaries watch passing cadet formations, circa 1941; P002:478; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Governor Sprague reviewing cadets, circa 1941; p002:479; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Dignitaries reviewing OSC Band, circa 1941; P002:480; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing OSC cadet band marching.
    - Cadet company formations march past OSC Band, circa 1941; P002:481; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Cadet formations marching on parade field, with cadet band playing.
    - Cadet company formation on parade field, circa 1941; P002:483; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Cadet companies and band on parade field.
    - dignitaries reviewing cadets, little girl in foreground, circa 1941; P002:484; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague reviewing cadet formations in background. Small girl walking on parade field in photo foreground.
    - Governor Sprague congratulating cadets, circa 1941; P002:485; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague congratulating cadet officers in formation.
    - Navy officer swearing in new recruits, circa 1943; P002:489a; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      US Navy officer swearing in new recruits. The Navy V-12 and Army ASTP programs on OSC campus are listed on reverse of print item P002:489. This photo appears on pg. 235 of the 1943 OSC Beaver Yearbook.
    - Navy officer swearing in new recruits, circa 1942, 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Same view as P002:489a. US Navy officer swearing in new recruits. The Navy V-12 and Army ASTP programs on OSC campus are listed on reverse of photo. This photo appears on pg. 235 of the 1943 OSC Beaver Yearbook.
    - Naval officer with new recruits, circa 1942; P002:491; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Navy officer seated at table speaking to group of recruits/cadets. Photograph is related to P002:490 with same group of students. Circa dating based on previous photograph being used in 1942 Beaver Yearbook.
    - Military officers speaking to group, circa 1942; P002:492; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Group of military officers (Navy and Army are seen) on stage speaking to group. The location is possibly the Memorial Union Ballroom. Grand piano is seen offstage. Photo is probably in the same small group of recruit photos.
    - OSC Women's rifle team, kneeling with weapons, circa 1943; P002:493; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Four college coed females with Army rifles. Previous description dates photograph to April 1943. The rifles are US Military 1903 Springfield Bolt Action, with special after market adjustable peep sights, most likely used for the precision rifle team. Photograph appears to be staged for publicity shot, possibly in the Oregon Stater or Beaver Yearbook.
    - OSC Women's rifle team, circa 1943; P002:494; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Cadet officer group pulling ballots for Military Ball, circa 1943; P002:495; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Group of cadet officers and NCO advisor pulling ballots for the Military Ball, probably 1942-43. Ballots for the "Little Colonel" queen of the ball. Photograph was probably produced for the Beaver yearbook (not published). Dress uniforms indicate WWII vintage. Location of photograph is in the Memorial Union.
    - Artillery on display outside Memorial Union, circa 1943; P002:496; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      One of OSC Artillery Unit's 75mm field guns on display outside Memorial Union. This photograph was used in college publications and was a finalist in a campus photo contest. The cadet and his girl behind the gun and officers in background indicate this scene may have been associated with the Military Ball held each year in the MU. Long evening gowns and dress uniforms also show formal affair.
    - Parade of officers and escorts at Military Ball, circa 1943; P002:497; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Military Ball procession of officers and their dates/escorts. The decorations are similar to the published photos in the 1943 Beaver annual for the Military Ball event.
    - OSC ROTC Cadet band on parade field, circa 1941; P002:498; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      OSC ROTC cadet band on parade field, probably inspection day. This photograph is in the same grouping showing Governor Sprague and President Strand on reviewing field. Uniforms are consistent with circa dating of early WWII.
    - Cadet band on parade field, 3 children follow, circa 1941; P002:499; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      OSC ROTC cadet band on parade field, probably inspection day. This photograph is in the same grouping showing Governor Sprague and President Strand on reviewing field. This photo includes 3 small children following the marching band.
    - President Strand and officers reviewing cadets, circa 1941; P002:500; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date. Governor Sprague and President Strand are seen reviewing cadet formations.
    - Cadet formations on parade field, color guard, circa 1941; P002:501; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Cadet Band marching in review, circa 1941; P002:502; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - President Strand and military officers review cadets, circa 1944; P002:503; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Photo includes August Strand with ROTC officers reviewing passing cadet formations. Colonel on left is wearing the late war issue "Ike" jacket dating the photo to 1944 or later. Officers are unidentified.
    - President Strand with Army Colonel and officers, circa 1944; P002:504; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Negative of P002:015. Photo includes August Strand with ROTC Military officers. Colonel on left shaking hands is wearing the late war issue "Ike" jacket dating the photo to 1944 or later. Probably taken on Inspection Day circa 1944. Good detail of uniforms and rank insignia. Officers are unidentified.
    - Officer making presentation to woman, circa 1942; P002:505; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Officer making presentation to an older woman circa 1942. Location of photo appears to be in the Armory.
    - Cadets marching on parade field, circa 1941; P002:506; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - ROTC Band marching on inspection day, circa 1941; P002:509; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - ROTC Cadets on parade field, circa 1941; P002:519; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Inspection Day, probably 1941. Other negatives in this grouping have notation of 1941 date.
    - Cadet formations ready for inspection, circa 1941; P002:523; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
    - Cadet officers grouped around flags on parade field, circa 1941; P002:525; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      ROTC Cadet officers in group around flags (OSC ROTC banners?). Photograph appears in the 1943 OSC Beaver yearbook.
    - ROTC Cadet formations on parade field, circa 1941; P002:529; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Cadets in company formation on parade field, probably inspection day. Other photographs in this grouping show various cadets marching past reviewing stand of dignitaries.
    - new recruits being sworn in on campus, circa 1942; P002:548; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      Army officer swearing in a group of young men on campus. Photograph may have been used in OSC publication. Same negative as P002:068.
    - Three Army Officers with Cadet, Armory in background, circa 1942; P002:549; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      US Army Officers (probably ROTC Instructors) with a civilian clothed student (Cadet?) in front of memorial plaque to General McAlexander on Armory building.
    - President Strand with 2 Army officers, circa 1944; P002:550; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      President August L. Strand (1942-1961) with two US Army officers. One officer is wearing the late WWII short "Ike Jacket". Location unknown, possibly outside Memorial Union.
    - President Strand with 2 Army officers, view #2, circa 1944; P002:551; 4X5 negative (Box 2)
      President August L. Strand (1942-1961) with two US Army officers. One officer is wearing the late WWII short "Ike Jacket". Location unknown, possibly outside Memorial Union. This view is related to P002:550, same subjects.
  - Strand, August L with ROTC officers, circa 1944; P002:015; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Photo includes August Strand with ROTC officers. Colonel on left shaking hands is wearing the late war issue "Ike" jacket dating the photo to 1944 or later. Good detail of uniforms and rank insignia. Officers are unidentified.
  - Award of Plaque to ROTC Cadet, circa 1945; P002:016; 1.0 4x5 negative; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Photograph from Oregon State College Library Picture Collection. Presentation of a plaque to Army ROTC cadet. No identification on personnel in photograph.
  - ROTC Cadets in line at Memorial Union, circa 1944; P002:017; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Photo marked in pen "News Bureau Photo". Photo of cadets in line to enter Memorial Union, some holding text books and folders. Uniforms indicate WWII vintage, ties tucked into shirts, all men wearing folding "Cutter" caps. Photograph appears in the 1944 Oregon State Beaver Yearbook, page 202.
  - Army ROTC Cadet assembly in Men's Gym, circa 1942; P002:018; 8X10 photographic print (Box 2)
    Stock photograph with marking "this belongs to John" written in pen at bottom. Large assembly of cadets, all seated in Men's Gym. Uniforms date photograph to WWII vintage.
  - 2 Men with Jeep with child on Hood, circa 1942; P002:019; 2X3 photographic print (Box 2)
    Two officers standing in front of WWII Jeep, small child standing on hood between them. Unknown location possibly CBI Theater. WWII vintage Jeep and uniforms, khaki, long sleeve shirts. Possibly USMC or Navy officers.
  - Army Personnel with L-2 Grasshopper aircraft, circa 1944; P002:022; 2X3 photographic print (Box 2)
    Three Army personnel with WWII L-2 Grasshopper Reconnaissance aircraft. Caption on reverse written in pen "I have returned - Corregidor" dating photograph to late 1944 based on quote by General MacArthur on 20 October 1944. The three officers in photo are wearing WWII vintage khaki uniforms with long sleeves. The aircraft in photo is the Taylorcraft L-2 Grasshopper, a small observation aircraft.
  - Officers receiving medals WWII, circa 1943; P002:024; 2X3 photographic print (Box 2)
    Small print with Oregon Stater "100 screen zinc" written in pencil on reverse. Also stamped with Beaver Engraving Co. mark. Photo shows 3 older officers receiving medal from US Army Air Corps Major General. Shoulder patches on 2 men indicate the US China-Burma-India Theater of operations. Center Officer receiving medal is of Brigadier General rank. Connection to Oregon Stater is unknown.
  - Oregon State College Rifles Drill Team, circa 1945; P002:025; 2X3 photographic print (Box 2)
    Oregon State College Rifles Drill Team performing in Men's Gymnasium. Photo can be dated prior to 1950 when Gill Coliseum opens. Assembly of students viewing drill team. Rifles in use are 1903 Springfield bolt action. By the end of WWII this rifle was used mainly for ceremonial drill teams and US Army Snipers.
  - Cadet officer inspecting rifle squad, circa 1942; P002:029; 2X3 photographic print (Box 2)